Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Arden d'Amico collection 1963-2003 IBT0033
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Arden D'Amico collection
1967-2003
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT0033
3.5 Linear Feet
This collections consists of material amassed by International Brotherhood of Teamsters teamster Arden "Art" D'Amico, dating from 163-2007.
Arrangement
Organized into 5 series: Contract and Agreements, General and Miscellaneous, IBT General President Elections, IBT Local 639, United Parcel Service.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by Arden D'Amico, 2012 [2012.065].
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of material amassed by International Brotherhood of Teamsters teamster Arden "Art" D'Amico, dating from 1963-2007. The records include contracts and agreements with various companies, primarily the United Parcel Service
Contracts; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions; Labor; Labor Unions -- Washington Metropolitan Area -- History -- 20th Century; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America; United Parcel Service
- Contracts and Agreements, 1967-2003; Series 1; 1.5 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains contracts and agreements for AFL-CIO and Teamsters unions dating from 1967-2003. The majority are National Master Freight and National Master United Parcel Service agreements and their supplements.
  - AFL-CIO Local 2093, 1982; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - IBT Local 639, 1996; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - IBT Local 804, 1993; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - National Master Freight Agreement and MD/DC Supplement, 1985-1988; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National Master Freight Agreement and MD/DC Supplement, 1991-1998; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Master Freight Agreement and Supplements, 2003; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - National Master United Parcel Service Agreement, 1979-1982; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National Master United Parcel Service Agreement, 1987-1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - National Master United Parcel Service Agreement, 1993; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - National Master United Parcel Service Agreement, 1993; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - National Master United Parcel Service Agreement, 1993; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - National Master United Parcel Service Agreement, 1997; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - National Master United Parcel Service Agreement, 1997; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - National Master United Parcel Service Agreement, 1997; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - National Master United Parcel Service Agreement, 1997; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - National Master United Parcel Service Agreement, 2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - National Master United Parcel Service Agreement, 2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - United Parcel Service Atlantic Area Agreement, 1967-1974; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- General and Miscellaneous, 1986-2002; Series 2; 1 Linear Feet
  This series contains general and miscellaneous materials related to the Teamsters union dating from 1986-2003. Included are IBT convention materials, constitutions, and rosters, as well as news clippings, newsletters, pamphlets and miscellaneous materials.
  - FedEx Teamsters, 1997; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - IBT 25th Convention Proceedings, 1996; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - IBT 26th Convention, 2001; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - IBT 26th Convention Committee Reports, 2001; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - IBT 26th Convention Official Delegate and Committee Member Lists, 2001; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - IBT 26th Convention Proceedings [1/2], 2001; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - IBT 26th Convention Proceedings [2/2], 2001; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - IBT 26th Convention Proposed Consitution, 2001; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - IBT Blue Ribbon Commission on Teamster Finances, 2002; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - IBT Constitutions, 1986-1991; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - IBT Constitutions, 1991-2001; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - IBT Rosters, 1999-2001; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - IBT Special Convention, 2002; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - News Clippings, 1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "News from the New Teamsters" Newsletter, 1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Rules for the IBT International Union Delegate and Officer Election, 1990; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - A Steward's Guide to Enforcing the National Agreement, 1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "The Teamster Leader" Newsletter, 1996; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "The Teamster" Magazine, 1996-2003; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Teamsters 100th Anniversary Celebration, 2003; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Teamsters for a Democratic Union, 1991-1998; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Teamsters Human Rights Conference, 1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Teamsters Pamphlets, 1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1997-2000; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- IBT General President Elections, 1996-2001; Series 3; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains IBT General President Election materials dating from 1996-2001. Included are campaign materials from both James P. Hoffa and Ron Carey, election results, and photographs. Also of note are materials detailing former IBT General President Ron Carey's election disqualification by Federal election monitors in 1997.
  - 2001 Election Results, Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - James P. Hoffa 1996 Campaign, Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - James P. Hoffa 2001 Campaign, Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - James P. Hoffa Inaugural Celebration, 1999; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hoffa Unity Slate IBT Convention News, 2001; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - National Press Club, 1997; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, 1998-1999; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Ron Carey, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Ron Carey 1996 Campaign, 1996-1997; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Ron Carey Federal Disqualification, 1997; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- IBT Local 639, 1982-2001; Series 4; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains materials produced by and about IBT Local 639 of Washington, DC, dating from 1982-1991. Included are correspondence, executive board minutes, newsletters, and local union election campaign materials from both The New Generation of Teamsters and the Concerned Members' slates.
  - Concerned Members' Slate, 1994; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1982-2001; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Executive Board Minutes / Special Concerns, 1983-1990; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Local 693 vs. United Parcel Service Legal Proceedings, 1991; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - The New Generation of Teamsters Slate, 1994-1995; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters, 1995-1997; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Rules for the 2000-2001 IBT International Union Delegate and Officer Elections, Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Local 639 Flag with various pins attached, ND; IBT0033 Series 4 (Box 8, Item 1)
  - Local 639 Pin Collection (2 bags), 1979-2005; IBT0033 Series 4 (Box 8, Item 2)
  - Local 639 Pouch with various pins inside, ND; IBT 0033 Series 4 (Box 8, Item 3)
- United Parcel Service, 1982-2001; Series 5; 1 Linear Feet
  This series contains material related to the United Parcel Service dating from 1982-2001. Most of the series details the 1997 UPS Teamsters strike through various correspondence, meeting notes, newsletters, magazines, news clippings, and contract campaign materials. The rest of the series is comprised of various other materials, including grievance and disciplinary forms, health/welfare/pension information, training information, and contracts and agreements.
  - Contracts and Agreements, 1983-1996; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1998; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Grievances and Disciplinary Action [1/2], 1983-1989; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Grievances and Disciplinary Action [2/2], 1984-1997; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Health, Welfare and Pension Information, 1986-2001; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - IBT Local 639 "Local Vocal" Newsletter, 1987-1997; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Notes, 1982-1997; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Newsletters, 1997; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - National Labor Relations Board Affidavit, 1990 August 9; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - News Clippings [1/2], 1987-1997; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - News Clippings [2/2], 1990-1997; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "The Teamster Leader" Newsletter, 1997; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "The Teamster" Magazine, 1990-1998; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Teamsters Contract Campaign, 1995-1997; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Teamsters Convoy Dispatch" Newsletter, 1993; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Teamsters UPS Contract Update" Newsletter, 1993-1998; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - UPS "Big Idea" Magazine, 1990-1996; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - UPS Teamsters Strike, 1997; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "UPS Teamsters for a Strong Contract" Newsletter, 1996; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - UPS Training, undated; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989-1999; Series 5 (Box 7, Folder 10)